Guide to the Americas collection, 1811-1920 MS 518
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VIII: Multi-country, 1811-1914; 242325
  - 1863. Kingsley, Vine Wright.French Intervention in America; Or, a Review of La France, Le Mexique, et Les Etas Confederes. France intervenes in Mexico during the American Civil War. Discusses the intentions of Napoleon III to raise Maximilian to power in Mexico. 22pp. (Pm, #48), 242330 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 1863. Chevalier, M.M. France, Mexico, and the Confederate States. Translated by Wm. Henry Hurlbut. Preface explains Hurlbut's motivation for the translation: it "has obtained a world-wide notoriety as embodying the first coherent view which has been made public of the designs of Napoleon III, in the New World." 15 pp. (Pm, #45), 242329 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 5-31-1869. [Mexico-U.S. Treaty] El G. Ignacio Romero Vargas, Gobernador Consttucional Interino Del Estado L.Y.S. De Puebla, A Sus Habitantes, Sabed…Puebla. Printed in four columns, in English and Spanish. A rare bilingual broadside printing a treaty between the United States and Mexico, following up the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo. (Br, #22), 242328 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 12-3-1908 Letter by Theodore Roosevelt on White House stationery, discussing events in Haiti, Santo Domingo, Cuba, Panama, and Venezuela. "... we have interfered in various different ways, and in each case of the immeasurable betterment of the people". To William Hale of the New York Times. (TLS, #59), 242327 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 11-13-1914. Wilson, Woodrow. Letter with press statement, both typed by Wilson. "… it is the purpose of the Administration to withdraw the troops of the United States from Vera Cruz on Monday…" To Secretary of War Lindley M. Garrison. (TLS, #30), 242326 (Box 5, Folder 19)